http://nihlibrary.nih.gov/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
The NIH Library physical space is currently closed. Library staff are still ready to assist you with your information needs.
See our online services, training, and resources, or ask us a question.
Search 2
Quick LinksQuick LinksCloseDatabasesDatabases SearchMicromedexPubMed @ NIHScopusUpToDateWeb of ScienceJournalsJournals SearchBrowse Journals via BrowzineJAMAJournal of Biological ChemistryNatureNEJMScienceOther Research ToolsBrowse by SubjecteBooks SearchEndNoteOnline CatalogRemote AccessRenew BooksSubject Guides
Log In
NIH Library HomeResourcesDatabasesDatabases SearchMicromedexPubMed @ NIHScopusUpToDateWeb of ScienceJournalsJournals SearchJAMAJournal of Biological ChemistryNEJMNaturePNASScienceOther Research ToolsBrowse by SubjecteBooks SearchOnline CatalogSubject GuidesEquipment, Software, & ToolsHHS Digital LibraryRenew BooksServicesLibrary Services3D PrintingBibliometricsBioinformatics SupportCustom Information SolutionsDataEditingInformationist ProgramSystematic ReviewsTechnology HubTraining ProgramTranslationsLiterature SearchProtocol SupportFacilitiesGreen EffortsLibrary WorkspacesLog In and Remote AccessSelf-Service PhotocopyTraining & EventsTraining TypesClassesCourse CatalogOnline TutorialsRequest a TutorialAbout UsGeneral InformationAddress & Key Phone NumbersAnnouncements & NewsHours & Holiday HoursLibrary Advisory CommitteeNIH Library CollectionNIH Library StatisticsStaff DirectoryStaff PublicationsVision, Mission, ValuesPolicies & ProceduresAccessibilityFor the PublicLibrary Privileges & BorrowingPrivacy PolicyGet HelpRequestsAsk a QuestionBioinformatics Resource RegistrationConsultations & TutorialsEditing RequestLiterature Search RequestOrder an Article, Book, or DocumentReport a ProblemSciFinder RegistrationSuggest a ResourceSuggest a TrainingTranslations RequestAdditional HelpFind Your LibrarianNIH Library FAQs
Log In
You are hereHomeAbout UsPrivacy Policy
Policies & Procedures
Accessibility
For the Public
Library Privileges & Borrowing
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Protecting your privacy is very important to the NIH Library. The NIH Library (NIHL) does not collect any personally identifiable information (PII) about you during your visit to our website, unless you choose to provide it to us through our web request systems. However, we do collect some data about your visit to our website to help us better understand how our users use the site and how to make it more helpful. We collect information from visitors who read, browse, and/or download information from our website. NIHL never collects information for commercial marketing or any purpose unrelated to the NIHL mission and goals.
Types of Information Collected by the NIH Library
The Domain from which you access the Internet.
The Internet Protocol (IP) address from your browser. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to a computer when surfing the Web.
The operating system you use, and information about the browser used when visiting the site.
The date and time that you access the library Web sites.
The pages that you visited.
The user name of any HHS or remote users will be retained with the NIHL proxy product manager.
Address of the Web site that connected you to an NIHL Web site (such as google.com or bing.com).
PII provided voluntarily by users of the library site to complete web requests. This may also include specific information provided to the library related to research, patents, or health related topics.
We use this information to measure the number of visitors to our site and its various sections and to help make our site more useful to visitors. This information cannot be used to identify you as an individual.
How the NIH Library Collects Information
The NIHL Web site uses a variety of different web-based software tools to gather information about how users navigate and interact with our websites. These software tools collect the type of information outlined in "Types of Information Collected by the NIH Library." These web-based software tools used by NIHL do not collect personally identifiable information (PII).
The Library occasionally uses online surveys to collect opinions and feedback from a random sample of visitors. The survey reports are available only to NIHL staff who evaluate Web site effectiveness, and other designated NIHL staff who require this information to perform their duties.
The NIH Library uses a third-party application to process web requests. Review the Desk Tracker privacy policy. (PDF)
How the NIH Library Uses Cookies
Session Cookies: We use session cookies for technical purposes such as to enable better navigation through our site. These cookies let our server know that you are continuing a visit to our site. The OMB Memo 10-22 Guidance defines our use of session cookies as "Usage Tier 1—Single Session." The policy says, "This tier encompasses any use of single session Web measurement and customization technologies."
Persistent Cookies: We use persistent cookies to enable a number of Web-based analytic tools. These tools allow us to differentiate between new and returning nihlibrary.nih.gov visitors. Persistent cookies remain on your computer between visits to nihlibrary.nih.gov until they expire. We also use persistent cookies to block repeated invitations to take the ACSI survey. The persistent cookies that block repeated survey invitations expire in 90 days. The OMB Memo 10-22 Guidance defines our use of persistent cookies as "Usage Tier 2—Multi-session without Personally Identifiable Information (PII)." The policy says, "This tier encompasses any use of multi-session Web measurement and customization technologies when no PII is collected."
How to Opt Out or Disable Cookies
If you do not wish to have session or persistent cookies placed on your computer, you can disable them using your Web browser. If you opt out of cookies, you will still have access to all information and resources at nihlibrary.nih.gov. Instructions for disabling or opting out of cookies in the most popular browsers are located at http://www.usa.gov/optout_instructions.shtml. Please note that by following the instructions to opt-out of cookies, you will disable cookies from all sources, not just those from nihlibrary.nih.gov.
How Personal Information is Protected
You do not have to give us personal information to visit the NIH Web sites. However, if you choose to receive alerts or e-newsletters, we collect your email address to complete the subscription process. If we store your personal information in a record system designed to retrieve information about you by personal identifier (name, personal email address, personal or mobile phone number, etc.), so that we may contact you, we will safeguard the information you provide to us in accordance with the Privacy Act of 1974, as amended (5 U.S.C. Section 552a).
External Links
We provide links from our Web pages to external Web sites because they provide information that may interest our users. This is provided as a convenience only. External links do not constitute an endorsement or an approval by NIHL for any of the products, services or opinions of the corporation or organizations. NIHL is not responsible for the legality or accuracy of information on externally linked sites, or for any costs incurred while using externally linked sites.
Use of Third Party Applications
NIHL uses third party applications which have been approved for use by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). These include FaceBook, Twitter, YouTube, and Google Analytics. None of these products or services are government owned or government operated; however, NIHL's use of these applications are government operated. No personally identifiable information is sought or maintained from any of these third party applications. If users of the third party applications choose to provide anything they might consider personally identifiable information (PII), users should know that they may be providing non-governmental third parties with access to their PII. A link to the official NIHL Web site and this privacy policy is provided when the third party application makes it possible.
Copyright Restrictions Applicable to NIH Staff
Access to electronic resources is restricted to NIH staff as established in license agreements between the NIHL and the resources producers/vendors. NIH staff who use these resources are authorized to print or download full or partial results of searches for personal or internal business or research use, as governed by the terms of the resources license agreements. Users cannot share access with, perform searches for, or provide results to non-NIH users, i.e. collaborators at other universities or research centers. NIH staff are not authorized to distribute data retrieved from the resources in any form (printed, electronically relayed, posted to public list services or bulletin boards, or magnetically stored) to, or for the benefit of, anyone who is not NIH staff. Nor is NIH staff permitted to create derivative databases from the resources except as noted above. Restrictions vary according to the resources producers/vendors. Please ask the NIH Library's Information Desk for more information (301-496-1080).NIH Library Service: About the LibraryNIH Subject: General
Last modified date: Thu, 11/07/2019 - 2:53pm
